# Michael Curran

### Developer

Passionate Computer Science student and web developer. Using HTML5 and CSS and JS to build all aspects of web applications. I pride myself on understanding and delivering on client's expectations through excellent communication and rational problem-solving. My experience has taught me that even the most daunting tasks a developer can face can be overcome by thorough research, strategic planning, and a thoughtful approach.

#### **Work Experience**

### **React Developer Contractor** with GreakTech

January 2021 - Current

Currently working with React and Next.js on a small team to create a campaign management platform. Responsibilities include,

- Identifying bugs and implementing fixes
- Creating and consuming REST API's and API calls
- Participating in code reviews.

### Back End Developer Intern at Mind Home

January 2021 - February 2021

Used Python to implement server-side logic and scripts for a SaaS platform that connects IoT devices to a central hub for smart homes.

# Web Developer at Freelance

March 2018 - Present

Currently advising and developing all aspects of client applications from web and graphic design to server-side back-end logic.

- Reduced bounce rates by up to 17% by simplifying UI/UX Design.
- Creating inspired and unique graphic designs and logos while adhering to the client's brand using Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop

# Kitchen Manager at Back East Bar & Grill

October 2014 - October 2019

Commended for having a great management style and excellent communication skills.

#### **Recent Personal Projects**

# **Brawl Buddy** created on MERN stack

Displays user statistics fetched from the official Brawlhalla API. Includes a ranked leaderboard, individual user statistics plus stat trends for highly ranked users, and a streaming tool to view stats per session. https://brawl-buddy.herokuapp.com

#### **Contact Details**

**Phone**: 386-690-0749

Email: Mcurran1722@gmail.com Location: Colorado Springs, CO Github: <u>Github.com/micurran</u> Portfolio: MiCurran.dev

#### **Expertise**

HTML & CSS	5 years
Javascript	5 years
Express.js	3 years
MYSQL & MongoDB	3 years
Node.js	3 years
REST API'S	3 years
React.js	2 years
NextJS	2 years
Angular2+	1 year

#### Certifications

CIW Site Development Associate

2019 - Present

**Volunteer Work** 

Volunteer Developer Spicy Green Book 2020 - 2021

Education

Computer Science Western Governors University 2019 - Present Computer Programming and

Analysis Daytona State College

2011 - 2013